hi everybody Welcome to Polar Ice
Creamery it's that time of year again
where all the festive stuff starts to
happen we're going to do our part and
make candy cane ice cream so if you want
to see what's involved stick around and
Santa will show
[Music]
you candy ice cream it's not really a
flavor that we had back in the UK it's a
big flavor here um in Canada and I think
America America at this time of year
what is Candy Cane Ice Cream it's really
simply a peppermint or mint ice cream
with candy cane pieces and or powder
through it depending on which one you
buy so it's going to be a nice simple
one to make let's get started by
crushing our candy canes right I don't
know how long I'm going to keep this hat
on it's warm anyway let's open
our candy canes Canadian Tire thank you
very
much let's get some of these
[Applause]
out how many are we going to need I
don't know
let's keep some for the tree and do that
many put those there right going to
crush these
up get that out you got PESA motar like
me great just get them in there and
give it a good
pounding I don't want it all powdered
but just start breaking us
up okay we don't want it super fine we
want to keep some of
those let me take a picture and show you
there we go we want to keep some of
those medium to small pieces there with
our
powder and with that done we're going to
pop that in here oh
look and put it in the
freezer I don't know why I said it like
that anyway onto the ice cream base this
is a nice easy peppermint ice cream base
I used this one in the Minter Wonderland
comparison video I think back in
2022 anyway what we've got here is we
got our milk and cream the hob is on and
we're just going to slowly warm that up
and what we have in here is our sucros
our dextrose milk powder and
stabilizer this is special ingredients
stabilizer if you don't know I love this
stuff I love the company they do some
really really nice handy products for
those that like to experiment with their
food anyway we going to get all of that
in there that will dissolve really
really quickly no heat required actually
to dissolve this but what we do need
heat for is that stabilizer so before
that gets up to temperature we're going
to take our two candy canes and get
those in there as well break up just so
they're a little bit easier to
dissolve and
stir you're going to bring this up
to somewhere between 75 and 80°
Centigrade for this stabilizer use a
different stabilizer then bring it up to
the temperature needed for that one and
then I will come back when that's done
so we're up to temperature here and I've
actually just turned the heat off and
I'm going to leave it here just slowly
ticking away for a few
minutes and we're going to get this in
the
container there we
[Music]
go and we've got our peppermint extract
to put in but we're going to put that in
when the base is cold okay so put that
aside right now just get this covered up
and get this in the fridge so the base
has been in the fridge completely
chilled down we're going to get it out
get it in the machine and churning and
load in the tub one thing to note is I
was going to put the peppermint extract
in it but actually there's enough flavor
that's come out of these candy canes to
flavor the whole base more than enough
so decide before you Churn it if you
want to put extract in put it in when
it's cold when your base has chilled
down in the fridge if you don't then
don't and when your churn is about 2 or
3 minutes before you're going to take it
out your machine
add in your frozen Candy Cane pieces and
then load it all in a container and put
it in the
freezer Candy Cane Ice Cream where's my
[Music]
hat there we
go got my hat candy cane ice cream let's
get some dished
up candy can and ice cream not a flavor
we had back in England but here we
[Music]
go
delicious I'm a little bit surprised
that just those two can canes in there
we're able to give that base as much
flavor as they
did I mean if you want to go over the
top then you know add another couple but
you're going to start playing with a
freezing point cuz they're just they're
pure sugar
so yeah really nice super smooth ice
cream no detectable ice lovely candy
cane flavor little bits of candy cane
scattered throughout big pieces small
pieces that is a Christmas ice cream
Perfection anyway I hope my hat
irritated you suitably I hope you had a
good year and for those that do
celebrate Christmas Happy Christmas for
those that don't celebrate Christmas
Happy Christmas and you know do whatever
you want to do at this time of year if
you do if you don't celebrate it then
just be happy doing whatever it is you
want to do okay so from everyone at
Polar Ice creamy which is me thank you
for coming along in 2023 there's been a
lot happening this year there's going to
be even more happening next year it's a
busy year for me next year I'll explain
more in the new year but there's a
couple more videos left for me in 2023
before I settle down to enjoy the
festive season with my
family and yeah you take care I'll see
you on the next one
oh